Rami Abo Obeid

Senior IT Support Specialist

Location: UAE, Abu Dhabi Mobile: +971502230349 Email: rami.aboobied1992@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>in/rami-abo-obied-b9748b11a/</u> Date of Birth: 08/11/1992 Nationality: Jordanian

Career Objective

Diligent professional with 8 years of work experience and proven knowledge of contract compliance, customer needs assessment, and key account management. Aiming to leverage my abilities to successfully fill the IT Field role at your company.

Experience

Senior IT Support Specialist

UAE – Abu Dhabi

Alef Education

December 2018 - present

- * Troubleshoot and performed data analysis and event analysis to assess the scope and impact of issues.
- * Delivered production support of complex high availability mission critical web-based software systems.
- * Mentored junior system engineers and coached team members in continuous integration and delivery events.
- * Supported after-hours critical incidents by working with teams to drive resolution.
- * Facilitated solutions with departments and individuals, communicating status to stakeholders.
- * Set up equipment for employee use, performed and ensured proper cables, operating systems, and appropriate software installed.

Prepared evaluations of software and hardware and recommended improvements and upgrades.

- * Installed and performed minor repairs to hardware, software, and peripheral equipment, following design and installation specifications.
- * Developed training materials and procedures, and trained users in properly using hardware and software Regarded computer software and hardware operation and resolved problems.
- *Maintained records of daily data communication transactions, problems, remedial actions taken, and installation activities.
- *Referred significant hardware and software problems and defective products to vendors and technicians for service.

- * Conferred with users, and conducted computer diagnostics to investigate and resolve problems and to provide technical assistance and support.
- * Oversaw daily performance of computer systems.
- * Analyse and fix end-user computer issues on Windows, Chromebooks, Android, Mac, and other platforms for applications including MS Office, Teams, Swift Assess, LMS, and Alef Platform.
- * Managing more than 600 users in government schools.
- * Follow the ITIL foundation process.
- * Coordinate and solve tickets of users and groups on P1, P2 and P3 incidents (Zoho Manage Engine Service Desk)
- * Windows Server/Desktops Installations and Licensing.
- * Delivered classroom-based training on the Microsoft suite of products.
- * Working on MDM and Air Watch Tools.
- * Working with the Administration on Office 365.
- * Troubleshooting LAN /WAN and Wireless Networks and Administer and support network operations and resolve the network issue in all Schools.
- * Ensuring applying the maximum availability for all critical and major impact cases.
- * Provides accurate information and supports Service Management in all areas.
- * Installation and Technical support for All servers Physical and virtual and Cloud Server Setup.
- * Daily checklist to ensure optimal operation of IT infrastructure
- * Resolve Hardware issues (Hard disk HDD & SSD hard drive, Ethernet)
- * Provide hardware and software support for all supported Personal Computers and Mobile.
- * Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, Tracert
- * Assisted and reviewed the planning and design of IT infrastructure architecture
- * Troubleshoot hardware and software issues in person, remotely and via phone.
- * Offer daily operations and systems support to users.
- * Resolve all issues in projectors and smart board (Fix the HDMI, and USB Cables, calibrate, adjust, and connect them to the LAN ...)
- * Perform daily operational checklist from school to confirm the operational readiness of ALEF at school, Verify functionality of hardware and software components. And make sure that there are any users (students, teachers and admins) are facing any issue.
- * Using Service Desk tools (ZOHO Manage Engine) for Upgrading, supporting, resolving, escalating, and following up on all issues relating to PCs or laptops, printers, phones, LAN, and WAN, projectors, Smartboard.

Target Scientific

June 2015 – November 2018

- *Assist with troubleshooting and data analysis, as well as event analysis to determine the scope and impact of issues.
- * Served as a mentor and coach for junior system engineers and provided coaching for team members during continuous integration and delivery processes.
- * Coordinated the installation and upgrade of enterprise infrastructure hardware and software.
- * Worked with teams to resolve after-hours critical incidents.
- * Recorded daily transactions, problems and remedial actions are taken, and installation activities.
- * Created training materials and procedures, and trained users on how to use hardware and software.
- * Attends conferences, seminars, and training sessions to keep current with rapidly.
- * Software and product training sessions on Hitachi interactive solutions Such as Intel education solutions, Net Support, Digital Signage, Projectors, and SmartBoard.
- * Configuring and maintaining the networked computer system, including Hardware, system software, and applications.
- * Management and maintenance of computer networks.
- * Fix and maintain all hardware issues and software issues.
- * VEQ IQ & EDR robotics Trainer and coordinator working on:-
- Assemble & disassemble VEX Products.
- Write a program coding for robotics functions.
- Build and train to build robotics with full functions & sensors.

Desktop / web Developer

UAE – ABU Dhabi

FreeLancer

2018 – Present

- * Planning, assessing and writing codes for desktop and web application.
- * Handling documentation, the customer requests and problems.
- * Handling User Requests & Reports adding new features and fixing errors.
- * Build Project using OOP (green code).
- * Building Assignment with C#, ASP.Net and SQL Server.
- * In-depth knowledge of HTML, CSS and JavaScript

* Experience in working with databases such as MS SQL Server, MySQL, and Entity Framework

Education

(M.S.) In Computer Science Very Good

Al Zarqa Private University – Jordan 2017 – present

(B.S.) In Computer Science Good

Al Balqa Applied University – Jordan 2010 – 2014

Skills

* Strong problem-solving skills

* Hardware and software troubleshooting

* Windows and Mac operating systems

* Team management

* Good presentation skills

* Customer service

* Cisco AP installation and configuration

* Strong communication skills

* Networking (TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP)

* Active Directory and Group Policy

* Technical support

* IT policy development

* Software trainee sessions

* Remote support tools (e.g. TeamViewer, Remote Desktop)

Courses with Certificate

* CCNA and CCNP from CISCO

* Communication skills people cert.

* ITIL Foundation V4 from people cert.

* SQL server management studio & SQL/PLSQL

* IT Support specialist from google

* ASP.NET MVC from Pioneers academy.

* C# Full course from Pioneers academy.

* HTML5 and CSS3 self-study.

* Google G-suit Trainee and administrator from Google

Projects

- Full projects created using C#, HTML, CSS and JS
- 1- Full point of sale system using C# and SQL Server database.
- 2- HR System from Al Daar-Al Bayda Consultant Company.
- 3- Portfolio website using HTML, CSS and JS.